Taft, Philip Papers 5541
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. Research/Subject Files
  - Hours of Labor, 1882-1963 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Letter from International Association of Machinists President A. J. Hayes to arbitrator Theodore Kheel criticizing report prepared at Cornell, "The Shorter Work Week," February 18, 1963; "Memorandum for Mr. Green" from AFL representative re efforts to obtain support for 30 hour week legislation in Congress, January 15, 1935; form letter to all labor representatives in Washington from AFL President Green, announcing meeting re 30 hour week legislation in Congress, April 3, 1935; notes. See also: Wages and Hours, Box 13, File Folder 27-28.
  - House Un-American Affairs Committee, 1947-1963 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    "Oral Statement of William Green, President AFL, Before the Committee on Un-American Activities of the House of Representatives on HR 1884 and HR 2122," against outlawing the Communist Party, March 25, 1947, 5 pages; booklet "House Un-American Activities Committee: Bulwark of Segregation," by National Committee to Abolish the House Un-American Activities Committee, c. 1963, 49 pages
  - Housing, 1936-1954 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Letter from AFL President Green to Congressman Steagall in support of low-income housing legislation, May 4, 1938, 3 pages; memoranda from AFL National Legislative representative W. C. Cushing re various housing bills, 1937-40; "Rom Report of the Executive Council to the Boston, 1943, Convention, AFL," re need for a post-war housing program, 2 pages; "Statement by William Green, President, AFL, on the General Housing Bill, S 1592, before Senate Banking and Currency Committee, December 4, 1945," 5 pages; typescript, "Housing Legislation" with handwritten note: "This was written for meeting before 1945 convention which was not held and this was not used. WCH 8/13/46," 5 pages; "Amendment to 1592: Extending Prevailing Wage Requirement to ALL FHA-insured Housing," 4 page manuscript by Housing Committee, AFL, April 13, 1946; statements by AFL Building and Construction Trades Department Chairman Richard Gray before Senate Banking and Currency Committee: (February 18, 1949, 9 pages plus 5 pages of attachments; January 17, 1950 re middle-income housing, 12 pages); "AFL Statement on Housing Legislation," January 31, 1949, 3 pages; "Statement of Defense Housing Policy," January 29, 1951, 4 pages; press releases; form letters; notes
  - Immigration, 1840-1953 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    "Statement Presented to the [House] Committee on Immigration and Naturalization ... by Jewish G. Hines, National Legislative Representative, AFL," opposing reduction in immigration quotas, March 20, 1946, 2 pages; "Statement of Mr. William Green, President of the AFL, Before the [House] Judiciary Committee," supporting emergency legislation to allow entry of displaced persons from Europe, 4 pages with 3 pages of charts and text, June 13, 1947; "Statement of Walter J. Mason, member National Legislative Committee, AFL, Before the [House] Subcommittee on Immigration" supporting Special Migration Act of 1952 (basically as above) June 3, 1952, 6 pages, before Senate subcommittee, May 28, 1953, 8 pages; "Statement of Boris Shishkin on behalf of the AFL Before the President's Commission on Immigration and Naturalization," October 28, 1952, 8 pages; "Summary of Contents of Emergency Migration Act of 1953," unsigned 5 page typescript, May 14, 1953; many notes re AFL's early position against immigration
  - Incorporation of Trade Unions, 1922-1946 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    "Why Trade Unions Should Not Incorporate," by Samuel Gompers, January 16, 1922, 3 pages; "Incorporation of Trade Unions," unsigned typescript, October 12, 1936, 4 pages; "Memorandum of Effect of Incorporation by a Union," by Joseph A. Padway, General Counsel, AFL, November 15, 1946
  - Industrial Relations Board, 1921-1934 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    "Confidential: Industrial Relations Boards," unsigned typescript, May 9, 1934, 3 pages; notes
  - Industrial Safety, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Resolutions adopted at a conference, January 17-19, 1910, calling for "Uniform Laws to Protect Human Life" in industrial jobs
  - Inflation, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Injunction and Anti-Injunction, 1891-1942 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Unsigned typescript "The Use of Injunctions in Labor Disputes," marked "Confidential" possibly scholarly paper, [1928], 42 pages; "The Clayton Anti-Trust Law" report of the Executive Council, AFL, to the AFL Annual Convention, November 1914, 12 pages; letter from Gompers to AFL Executive Council re growing use of court injunctions, February 8, 1922, 7 pages; memos from AFL legislative representatives, 1930 and 1939; "Text of the Anti-Injunction Bill," approved by the AFL Executive Council, August 14, 1931, 4 printed pages; "The Inequity of Injunctions," an address by Illinois State Federation of Labor Secretary-Treasurer OLander at the Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia, August 4, 1930, 17 pages; statement adopted by AFL Executive Council, "Analysis of Thurman Arnold's Statement Made Before T.N.E.C. on February 13, 1941," 7 pages; form letters; notes
  - International Labor Union, 1878 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Iron Workers Local Union, 1951-1954 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Unsigned typescript, "The International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers," 1953, 11 pages; booklets (re Group Insurance and Annual Report, 1954) of Structural Iron Workers Local Number 1
  - Jobs For All Program, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Jurisdictional Disputes, 1887-1965 (Box 7, Folder 30-32)
    "Recent Jurisdictional Developments in Organized Labor," 31 page manuscript from reprint series 8, Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations, University of Michigan - Wayne State University, prepared by Mark L. Kahn, Professor of Economics, n.d., c. 1957; "Appeals Board Plan for the Settlement of Jurisdictional Disputes," August 25, 1965, 17 pages; legal documents re Carpenters' dispute in Maine, 1968; mediation cases, 1962-65; copious handwritten notes
  - Jurisdictional - Trusteeship - Notes, 1916-1950 (Box 7, Folder 32a-b)
    R outline. See also: CIO folders, Box 4
  - Korean War Defense Mobilization, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    "Statement by the Executive Council, AFL" re defense mobilization, August 10, 1950, 2 pages, sent to Senators; Executive Council minutes, adopting press statement re housing policy during Korean mobilization, August 8, 1950, 3 pages; notes
  - Labor Banks and Insurance Company, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    Form letter to AFL affiliates announcing conference on insurance, with attached letter from the AFL Insurance Committee and results of conference endorsing report, June 1925; minutes of insurance conference, with list of delegates attending, July 21, 1925, 3 pages; letter from Union Cooperative Insurance Association to AFL official, July 24, 1925; "Did You Hear About Jones? A True Story" pamphlet by the Union Cooperative Insurance Association, urging union members to take out insurance policies with the Association, 3 pages, c. 1924-25.
  - Labor Department, 1913-1962 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    "A Bill, An Act - Proposed by Secretary Doak-Draft," n.d., to provide for the establishment of a national employment system, 2 pages; "Oral Statement of William Green, President AFL, Before the Senate Appropriations Committee ... re Labor Department Budget," April 14, 1947, 11 pages; "The Labor Secretary and Labor Questions," printed 7 page booklet by William Barr, President, National Founders' Association, criticizing the new Labor Secretary Wilson as a partisan of organized labor, 1913; "Proclamation by the President of the United States Commemorating the 50th Anniversary of the U.S. Department of Labor, May 2, 1962."
  - Labor-Management Conference, 1919-1945 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    Letter from President Gompers to AFL Executive Council asking for advice re Presidential Industrial Conference, September 26, 1919, 3 pages; form letter to AFL affiliates, urging participation in Labor-Management Committees in war production plants, with "Outline for Labor-Management Committees," attached, 4 pages, June 21, 1943; Executive Committee minutes re Labor-Management Conference, August 9, 1945, 7 pages, and October 23, 1945, 3 pages; notes
  - Labor Newspapers and Periodicals, 1836-1940 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Labor Parties, 1886-1936 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    "The Failure of an American Labor Party. The Politics of the CIO in the New Deal," n.d., outline for lecture or article, possibly by Taft, 5 pages; notes; form letters
  - Labor's League for Political Education, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    Fact sheet and chronological summary re formation of LLPE with list of officers; "Minutes of the Special Meeting of the Executive Council, AFL," December 4, 1947, to discuss formation of LLPE, 6 pages; "Conference of Officers of National and International Unions," to set up LLPE, December 5, 1947, 22 pages; "Recommendations of the Executive Council, AFL, to the Conference of International Presidents," December 5, 1947, 10 pages; press release announcing formation of LLPE, December 10, 1947, 3 pages; LLPE Directory of State Affiliates, 7 pages; notes; form letters
  - Labor's League for Political Education, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    Minutes of Meeting of Administrative Committee of LLPE, January 6, 1948, 4 pages and February 4 and 5, 1948, 21 pages; reports (Department of Political Direction, July 22, 12 pages, September 21, 3 pages, November 15, 4 pages, and December 14, 3 pages; Department of Public Relations, July 22, 9 pages, August 25, 6 pages, and September 21, 1 page; Department of Finance, August 25, 6 pages, September 21, 7 pages, November 12, 9 pages, and December 14, 20 pages; Department of Organization, August 25, 2 pages and September 21, 1 page); recommendations of the Administrative Committee to the National Committee of LLPE, November 17, 1948, 1 page; letter from AFL President Green to LLPE Director Keenan, presenting $20,583.40 check from AFL to LLPE, December 4, 1948; press releases, many form letters
  - Labor's League for Political Education, 1949-1954 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    Memo to all U.S. Senators and Representatives from LLPE: "Peoria Manufacturers' Propaganda Backfires!" re repeal of Taft-Hartley law, June 9, 1949, 3 pages; LLPE Department of Finance Report on the Educational Fund, July 29, 1949, 8 pages, January 1950, 7 pages, and August 11, 1954, 5 pages; on the Political Fund, May 13, 1949, 12 pages; LLPE Department of Public Relations Report, May 7, 1949, 1 page; LLPE Department of Political Direction Report, May 7, 1949, 2 pages; LLPE Radio Department Report, May 7, 1949, 2 pages; Report on LLPE Newspaper, May 7, 1949, 2 pages; partial minutes, LLPE Tri-Cities Chapter, October 22, 1949, 2 pages; numerous newsletters and publications, including "Minutes of the National Committee of LLPE," October 5, 1949 and September 24, 1951 and LLPE Senate Voting Record - 1947-52," 5 pages
  - Labor's Non-Partisan Political League, 1938-1944 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    Letters and form letters from AFL President Green to AFL affiliated unions, etc., condemning Labor's Non-Partisan League as CIO agency, 1938-39; form letter from Labor's Non-Partisan League to members of the House of Representatives, opposing further funding of the Dies Committee, January 31, 1939, 3 pages; letter to green from AFL Vice-President George Harrison re non-involvement with Labor's Non-Partisan Political League, March 22, 1944; miscellaneous correspondence
  - Ladies Garment Workers Union, 1925-1963 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    "The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union," unsigned typescript, November 25, 1952, 13 pages; numerous clippings, notes and brochures
  - Landis Award, 1921-1926 (Box 7, Folder 44-46)
    Notes; photocopies of articles; brochures
  - Landrum-Griffin Act, 1958-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    "Government Regulation of Internal Union Affairs Affecting the Rights of Members," 102 page manuscript prepared by the Library of Congress Legislative Reference Service, May 1, 1958; brochures
  - Landrum-Griffin Material, 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Court cases, correspondence, notes, esp. re elections
  - Legal Defense (National Labor Defense Council), 1923-1938 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Correspondence; notes
  - Legislative Activity, 1882-1935 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    "Legislative Committee," 7 page manuscript by W. C. Roberts, December 1922; "Memo: for President Green," 7 page outline of pending Congressional legislation, February 18, 1926; "Instructions as to Legislation," 5 page summary of resolutions passed at AFL convention re pending Congressional legislation forwarded to AFL Legislative Committee for action, 1926; "Bills in Which Labor Was Interested that Became Law During 70th Congress," 1 page, c. 1927; letter to Chicago Tribune reporter from AFL Legislative Committee Chairman, objecting to representation of AFL legislative expenditure in news article, 3 pages, September 2, 1927; report re "Legislative Situation" to Executive Council meeting, 9 pages, January 17, 1928 and 9 pages, January 13, 1931; "List of Bills in Which Labor is Vitally Interested," 2 pages, April 10, 1928; "Memo for Mr. Green" re state legislation on Small and Chattel Loans, 4 pages, January 29, 1934; report of legislative Committee to AFL convention detailing 101 actions of the Committee, 38 pages, with cover letter to John L. Lewis, November 8, 1935; numerous telegrams from AFL President Green to state labor leaders urging them to wire their legislators in support of Walsh government contract bill, August 21, 1935; notes
  - Legislative Activity, 1936-1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Letter to Speaker of the House from AFL President Green, opposing Frazier- Lemke Act as inflationary, May 13, 1936; meeting of the Legislative Conference of the AFL, minutes, 4 pages, November 17, 1937, and 3 pages, February 17, 1938; minutes of meeting on Wages and Hours Conference, November 20, 1937, 4 pages; "Memo for Mr. Green: Republican Assignments for House Committee on Rules," 2 pages, January 19, 1939, re laws passed of interest to labor, 2 pages, June 28, 1939; minutes of the meeting of National Joint Legislative Conference, AFL and the Railroad Brotherhoods, 8 pages, January 19, 1945, 3 pages, May 27, 1946, and 3 pages, January 14, 1948; "Statement by the Executive Council, AFL," denouncing 79th Congress, 2 pages, August 12, 1946; memo to President Green listing 136 subjects referred to AFL Legislative Committee, 3 pages, January 21, 1948; "Statement by William Green, President, AFL" re collective bargaining legislation, 5 pages, n.d.; "Tentative list of Record Notes for Basis of Judging Congressional Candidates," 2 pages, May 26, 1948; AFL Press release re Taft-Hartley watchdog committee, March 15, 1948; resolution establishing AFL National Legislative Council, adopted at 1948 Convention, 2 pages; statement by AFL executive Matthew Woll, denouncing 80th Congress, 2 pages, July 19, 1948; memo to President Green from chairman of Legislative Committee, recommending improvements for Committee, 3 pages, March 10, 1949; list of bills supported by AFL in 80th Congress, September 9, 1949, 3 pages; "Analysis of `Your Congressional Scorecard, First Session, 81st Congress, 1949,'" unsigned, 4 pages; "Minutes of the Meeting of the National Legislative Council, AFL," March 21, 1950, 6 pages; booklet "Legislative Achievements of the AFL," January 1, 1953, 42 pages; copies of the American Federationist; form letters; notes.
  - Life Insurance Agents, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Loggers and Lumbermen, 1917-1950 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    "Loggers and Lumbermen," unsigned typescript, c. 1950, 13 pages
  - Machinists, 1917-1951 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    "The Machinists," 8 page typescript with hand notation "Paid 12/29/51 Taft"; letter from AFL President Gompers to U.S. Secretary of War re manufacturers' use of military exemption status to force workers to accept lower wages, November 16, 1917; correspondence between AFL President Green and Hamilton (Canada) Trades and Labor Council re refusal to recognize IAM delegates, March and July 1938; correspondence re various jurisdictional disputes, especially with CIO Maritime Federation of the Pacific, 1938-50; non-raiding agreement between IAM (AFL) and UAW (CIO), January 7, 1944 for duration of World War II; minutes of the AFL Executive Council, August 9, 1950 re re-affiliation of IAM with AFL, 8 pages, May 19, 1952 re jurisdictional dispute with Carpenters
  - Machinists - Publications and Notes, 1898-1968 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    IAM publications: Speed Facts, April 3, 15, 22 and 29, 1968; Aero Facts, March 22, April 12 and 26, 1968; Machinists Monthly Journal, "Machinists on the March, 1888-1950," May 1950; many notes
  - Maritime - Clippings, 1939-1961 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
    Mostly from 1939
  - Maritime - General, 1863-1963 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    "Seamen vs. Longshoremen - Arbitrator's Decision and Award," 3 strips of galley proofs, October 21, 1907; advisory opinion by Taft re appropriate bargaining unit for the Boston Naval Shipyard, July 13, 1963, 24 pages; notes. See also: Waterfront Employers, Box 13, File Folder 29-31. See also: Subsidies - Ship, Box 11, File Folder 11.
  - Maritime - Longshoremen - General, 1945-1966 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    "The Longshoremen," unsigned typescript, hand dated: "Paid 11/10/51," 7 pages; "[Overtime] In the Longshore Industry," 74 pages, [1945]; "The Response of Waterfront Union to Technological Change - the Experience with Containerization," with hand notation "P. Ross 1966," 139 pages; "Cry Baby Dewey," broadside by ILA (Independent), n.d.; "Report and Recommendations of AFL-CIO Executive Council Committee Respecting Application of International Longshoremen's Association (Independent) For Affiliation with the AFL-CIO," 15 pages, August 17, 1959; notes
  - Maritime - Longshoremen, ILA, 1919-1952 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Clippings and notes
  - Maritime - Longshoremen, KA - Court Case, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    New York Southern District Court civil action between ILA members and Huron Stevedoring Corporation, Bay Ridge Operating Co., Inc., "Finding of Fact and Conclusions of Law Suggested by Defendants", "Defendants' Comments of Plaintiffs' `Summary of Evidence and Proposed Findings'", "Defendants' Reply Brief", c. 1949
  - Maritime - Longshoremen, ILWU and Pacific, 1889-1948 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    "The Longshore Slow-Down," by F. P. Fosie, before Association of Pacific Coast Port Authorities re International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU) as vicious spoilers who "crucified" Pacific industry, September 9. 1940, 22 pages; "Seven Years - Foresight vs. Hindsight," by F. P. Fosie, before mixed labor-management audience at Industrial Relations Conference re working together in a spirit of trust as one big family, March 27, 1941, 21 pages; "Longshore Contract Proposal," adopted by Caucus of ILWU, August 31, 1945, 7 pages; notes re 1934 strike; miscellaneous notes. See also: Communists - CIO Infiltration, Box 4, File Folder 20.
  - Maritime - Longshoremen - New York City/New York State Reports, 1950-1954 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Reports of the Mayor's Joint Committee on Port Industry: (by Subcommittee on Pier Rentals and Insurance, January 18, 1951, 7 pages; by Subcommittee on the Perishable Foods Industry, n.d., 8 pages; by Subcommittee on Availability of Waterfront Facilities For Stevedores or Terminal Operations, August 6, 1951, 9 pages; by Subcommittee #5 on Labor Conditions Affecting Waterfront Commerce, August 9, 1951, 39 pages; by one member of Subcommittee #5, on New York Shipping Association letterhead, September 10, 1951, 8 pages); Report by Chairman of New York State Board of Mediation to New York Governor Dewey re dispute between ILA (AFL), ILA (Independent) and New York Shipping Association, December 28, 1953, 15 pages plus 4 page appendix; "Interim Report on Current Work Stoppage," by Waterfront Commission of New York Harbor, March 25, 1954, 12 pages plus 4 page appendix. See also: Racketeering - International Longshoremen's Association, Box 10, File Folder 9
  - Maritime - Longshoremen - New York City/New York State Reports, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 17a)
    "Final Report to the Industrial Commissioner, State of New York, from Board of Inquiry on Longshore Industry Work Stoppage, October-November 1951, Port of New York," January 22, 1952, 97 pages; "Statement of the ILA (AFL) on the Report, dated January 22, 1952, of Industrial Commissioner Corsi's Board of Inquiry," n.d., 114 pages.
  - Maritime - Maritime Commission, U.S., 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Letter from AFL President Green to Chairman of U.S. Maritime Commission re AFL as upholder of agreements, opponent of sit-down strikes, urging Commission to abandon its neutral stance, August 19, 1937; memorandum for President Green re legislation sponsored by the Maritime Commission, April 19, 1938, 3 pages
  - Maritime - Maritime Federation of the Pacific, 1935-1941 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    Reprint "The Rise and Fall of the Maritime Federation of the Pacific, 1935-1941" by R. J. Lampman, University of Washington, n.d., 4 pages; copy "The Voice of the Federation - Federation Moves to Secure Labor Rights for Pacific," mostly copies of letters to Secretary of Labor from Maritime Federation of Pacific, December 5, 1935, 7 pages
  - Maritime - Merchant Marine - Annual Reports, 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Maritime - Merchant Marine - Publications, 1941-1960 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    American Seaman, by the American Seamen's Friend Society, Volume 1, Number 1, Winter-Spring 1941 and Volume IV, Number 1, Winter 1944; "American Merchant Marine Policy After the War," confidential, for limited circulation, by the Council on Foreign Relations, June 1944, 26 pages; "Unionism and Democracy in the Merchant Marine," book review reprinted from Labor History, July 1960
  - Maritime - National Maritime Union (NMU), 1940-1966 (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
    We Accuse (from the record), printed book by leaders of non-Communist faction of NMU, n.d. 192 pages; agreement between NMU and unnamed company, January 20, 1940 with Addenda 1-4, 5/1/1940, 2/10/1941, 5/3 and 16/1941; "Hiring Halls In the Maritime Industry - A Summary Including Excerpts From Decision by an N.L.R.B. Trial Examiner In a Case Involving Great Lakes Carriers and the NMU, CIO," c. 1948, 18 pages; letter to NMU President Joseph Curran from Harry Bridges, President, International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, inviting NMU to a preliminary Conference of Maritime Union, December 29, 1945; letter from Committee for Democratic Unionism (CDU) re NMU expulsions, President Curran's conduct, July 21, 1950; publications: (CDU Bulletin, March, May, July, August 1950; Pilot, January 24, 1941; NMU Rank and File Pilot, July 1, 1950; NMU Independent Caucus Newsletter, December 23, 1949
  - Maritime - National Maritime Union (NMU), 1940-1966 (Box 8, Folder 22-23 cont)
    booklets "Hold That Meeting!" September 1943, "Pork Chops and Politics" by Joseph Curran, 1952); form letters: (outlining NMU revised National Shipping rules, May 28, 1940, 6 pages; outlining NMU activities, pending legislation, apparently sent to non-union prominent citizens, March 28, 1949, 3 pages; "NMU Independent Caucus - What is the NMU Independent Caucus?" n.d., 6 pages; "A Statement to NMU Members by the Committee for Democratic Unionism," n.d. 4 pages; "Call for an Emergency Rank and File Conference of the NMU in New York on Sunday, February 19, 1950," with Spanish translation on verso; flyer by Maritime May Day Committee calling for May Day March, n.d.); "Statement on NMU Situation from Norman Thomas," on behalf of anti-Curran anti-Communists, January 20, 1950, 14 pages; NMU sample ballot, 1949; notes.